They obeyed but one command
March or Die is a drama, adventure, war film directed by Dick Richards.
Just after World War I, Major Foster is incorporating new recruits into his French Foreign Legion platoon when he is sent to his former remote outpost located in the
French Morocco to protect an archaeological excavation from El Krim, a Rifian leader who intends to unite all local tribes to fight the colonial government…
Major William Sherman Foster, played by Gene Hackman.
Marco Segrain, played by Terence Hill.
Simone Picard, played by Catherine Deneuve.
François Marneau, played by Max von Sydow.
El Krim, played by Ian Holm.
Ivan, played by Jack O'Halloran.
March or Die is a 1977 British war drama film directed by Dick Richards and starring Gene
Hackman, Terence Hill, Catherine Deneuve, Max von Sydow, and Sir Ian Holm.
The film celebrates the 1920s French Foreign Legion, whose Major Foster (Hackman), a war-weary American haunted by his memories of the recently ended Great War, is assigned to
protect a group of archaeologists at a dig site in Erfoud in Morocco from Bedouin revolutionaries led by El-Krim (based on the Moroccan revolutionary Abd el-Krim).
The song "Plaisir d'amour", a tune about lost love and regret, is played
repeatedly throughout the story as the film's theme song.
The film explores themes of gypsy, foreign legion,
morocco, sahara desert, post world war i.
The tone is emotional.